## Michael Grünberger

45 Wissey Way, Ely CB6 2WN 07724 818185 • mgruenb@gmail.com

## **Personal statement**

A professional and successful software developer with over 20 years experience in programming, databases and system administration. Up-to-date knowledge of the latest programming languages, frameworks and tools through teaching professional IT courses from beginners to advanced level and through working on a large number of IT projects as senior and lead developer.

Management experience working closely with customers and in-depth technical knowledge make me the ideal candidate for this position.

## **Key Skills**

- Software Development skills in a wide range of programming languages
- Experience in keeping Linux servers on-line 24/7
- Advanced database skills
- Business experience
- Degree in European Business and Management Information Systems (Wirtschaftsinformatik)
- EU national with full settled status in UK

## **Technical Skills**

The following is a list of tools and languages I have used during the last 2 years:

• PHP7, Symfony (3+4), Laravel (5+6), Vue, React, REST (Swagger, Postman), GitFlow, AWS (Textract), Google Vision, Microsoft Azure (OCR + ChatBot)

Other tools and languages I have used in the past:

 Java, C, C++, C#, Perl, Python, PHP, Bash, JavaScript, XML, Web services (REST and SOAP), HTML, Jquery, Bootstrap, Git, Eclipse, Visual Studio, Windows Server (2000 onwards), Linux (many distros since 1999), Apache, Tomcat, MySQL, Sybase, MS SQL, Postgresql

## **Employment History**

#### Senior Developer, PlanNet Technolgy, Munich Germany

(Freelance since July 2019)

As I have moved back to the UK I now work remotely as freelancer for PlanNet Technology

- Currently I'm working on the following projects:
  - o E wie Einfach ( <u>https://www.e-wie.einfach.de</u> ) API: My role as senior developer is to coordinate different backend teams, designing the architecture and coordinating with the customer and development teams from other companies. Hands-on development is mostly on the PHP Symfony3+4 backends (REST API)
  - o **E wie Einfach OCR**: This is a tool using MS Azure which allows potential customers to scan their old gas and electricity invoices and then suggests a new cheaper rate. I've designed the system architecture, planned the epics and user stories, set-up the servers (test, stage, live) and and wrote most of the Symfony4 backend code with two Junior Devs. We used GitFlow, Jira and Jenkins for development and deployment.

#### Senior+Lead Developer, PlanNet Technolgy, Munich Germany

(Januar 2018 – June 2019)

Senior Developer and Team Lead working on various mid/large size projects. Team sizes vary between 2 and 10 devs depending on project plus PMs, concepters, designers. All projects Agile/Scrum (using Jira and Confuence). I'd be happy to explain the projects in more detail during the interview, but I can't list them here as they are not my IP.

Achievements and responsibilities:

- Cost estimation
- User stories/ business processes
- System architecture
- Team Management, dailies, assign tickets
- Code refactoring (SOA, Test-driven development)
- Hands on development
- DB design
- Security and performance reviews

## Company Director/ Trainer, Cambridge IT Courses Ltd, UK

(April 2002 - December 2017)

Achievements and responsibilities:

- Working with customers to tailor individual courses to their needs from advanced programming courses to courses in high-throughput databases
- Designing and delivering courses from beginners to advanced, for a list of courses see:
- http://cambridge-it-courses.co.uk/
- Starting and growing a business from freelance trainer to employing a dozen trainers
- Managing my assistant and working as a team to organise courses around the UK
- · Managing all financial matters, profit and loss accounts and company reports

## Senior Scientific Software Developer, University of Cambridge, UK

(April 2000 - December 2017)

I've worked on a number of international research projects during my time at the University which usually last between a couple of months and a few years. All projects were completed in time and on budget. For the following (selected) projects I was the senior developer and software architect and all projects included collaboration with partners from around the world. I was involved in all stages of the software development life cycle:

- STORE (http://storedb.org/): Linux + Windows system administration (Apache, Tomcat), software development (PHP, Java, JQuery), ontology integration, web services (SOAP), database administration (MySQL, Postgresql)
- CASIMIR (http://www.casimir.org.uk/): Linux system administration (Apache, Tomcat), software development (PHP, Java, Perl), ontology integration, description logic based reasoning on large data sets, web services (SOAP), databases (Postgres, MySOL)
- ERA-PRO (http://www.bfs.de/EN/bfs/science-research/projects/era/era\_node.html): Software development (PHP), ontology integration, web services (SOAP), database administration (MySOL)
- Pathbase (www.pathbase.net): Linux and Windows system administration (Apache, Tomcat, IIS), software development (PHP, Java, Perl, C), ontology integration and development (MPATH), web services (SOAP), databases (Sybase, Postgres, MySQL)

#### Software Developer, self-employed

(April 2002 - December 2017)

Achievements and responsibilities:

• Over the years I've worked as a developer on dozens of software development projects. The projects range from small web sites where I worked directly with customers to large complex projects where I worked as part of a team (sometimes international).

The following is a list of tools and languages I have used during the last 2 years:

PHP7, Symfony (3+4), Laravel (5+6), Vue, React, REST (Swagger, Postman), GitFlow, AWS (Textract), Google Vision, Microsoft Azure (OCR + ChatBot)

Other tools and languages I have used in the past:

- Java, C, C++, C#, Perl, Python, PHP, Bash, JavaScript, XML, Web services (REST and SOAP), HTML, Jquery, Bootstrap, Git, Eclipse, Visual Studio, Windows Server (2000 onwards), Linux (many distros since 1999), Apache, Tomcat, MySQL, Sybase, MS SQL, Postgresgl
- References and a list of projects and details are available on request.

## **Previous Employment**

(1995-2005)

IT Trainer, Bytesize IT Cambridge, UK

(May 2003 – December 2005)

Part time trainer for Linux, Perl, PHP, MySQL, XML, MS Office

Software developer, Netcentric Systems Cambridge, UK

(January 1999 - July 1999)

Java and web development placement

Web developer, AMECO Beijing, China

(June 1998 - December 1998)

Web developer placement

Personnel administrator, Luftwaffe Erding, Germany

(1995 - 1996)

Military service as personnel administrator

#### **Education**

# Fachhochschule Landshut, Germany/ Anglia University Cambridge, UK (1996-2000)

BA(Hons) and Diplom-Betriebswirt (FH) 2-1 in European Business and Management Information Systems. Modules included: Strategic Management, International Management, Organisation, Financial Management, Personnel+HR, International Marketing, Business Information Systems. My dissertation was on the internal workings of the Java Virtual Machine and a web-enabled spreadsheet for sharing financial data over the Internet.

## **Fachoberschule Freising, Germany (College)**

(1994-1995)

A-level (equivalent) focused on Business Administration. Graduated best in school.

#### **Hobbies & Interests**

I'm a keen cyclist involved in a number of local cycling clubs. I'm also a founding member of the Ely Cycling Campaign where I serve on the committee as Treasurer and where we're working with the council to make Ely more people friendly and less car-centric.

#### References

References are available upon request.